058-458-6484 (Israel) 201-994-6484 (US) ari.abramowitz1@gmail.com

Ari Abramowitz Senior Software Engineer

ariabramowitz.me linkedin.com/in/ariabr github.com/ariabr

Summary

Fullstack software engineer passionate about solving complex problems, mentoring others, and bringing ideas to life. Experienced in both startup and agile environments, where I combine creative problem-solving with a focus on clean, efficient code.

Skills

Frontend: JavaScript, React, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Material-UI

Backend: Python, Django, Flask, Node, Java, Spring, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Firebase

Experience

Senior Fullstack Engineer | Centers Health Care

2023 - Present

- · Developed software to streamline AR management for 80,000+ residents in 80 facilities throughout the US
- · Managed team of engineers in completing software projects
- · Contributed to the process of transforming business requirements into actionable tickets
- · Mentored team members on software development practices

Fullstack Software Engineer | Centers Health Care

2020 - 2023

- · Approved and deployed code across 15+ projects
- · Improved efficiency of lab processing 2,000+ COVID tests per day by building an app to track sample history
- · Improved code quality by performing initial and final code reviews for a team of 10 developers
- · Wrote clear and detailed documentation to ease future development

Founder & Automation Developer | Rally4Israel (rally4israel.com)

2024 - Present

- · Developed and maintained a platform supporting Israel and the Jewish community, attracting 1.2k+ users
- · Wrote and compiled rally materials into a centralized, user-friendly toolkit to aid event organizers
- · Built a centralized rally calendar with automation scripts to sync events and post updates on social media
- · Evaluated and implemented tools to balance functionality and user experience

Software Developer | Taryag Analytics

2019 - 2020

- Enabled 2020 Q1 beta launch by developing frontend and backend for six new text analysis features
- · Improved comparative analysis capabilities by building a web-scraping ETL process to load new source data

Powered by Sefaria Contest

2020

· Built a 3D family tree visualizer, earning Honorable Mention and featured as a showcase project

The Ezrat Nashim Database

2018 - Present

Designed and developed crowdsourced website to aid users in assessing local synagogue options

Code Contributions

Supply Match (8,000+ users): Configured DB backups for site pairing donations with soldiers in need	2023
Django Easy Audit (6,000+ weekly downloads): Coded bug fix for database auditing package	2022
Mindful Internet Use (1000+ users): Fixed frontend bug in Chrome productivity extension	2020

Education

Continuing Education

•	Python 3: Deep Dive (Dr. Fred Baptiste)	2024
	Bash Mastery: The Complete Guide to Bash Shell Scripting (Ziyad Yehia)	2021

· Test-Driven Development with Python (Harry Percival) 2021

Bloc | Web Developer Track

2019

· Mastered software engineering fundamentals by building 5 cloud-hosted web apps in an 8-month bootcamp

Rutgers University | BA | Summa Cum Laude | GPA: 3.94

2018

- · Majors: Philosophy, Jewish Studies; Minor: Religion
- · Semester Abroad: Honors Program, The Hebrew University of Jerusalem
- · Honor societies: Phi Beta Kappa; Natl. Society of Collegiate Scholars; Natl. Society of Leadership and Success